Hello my friends today I'll show you how to embed javascript scripts on your website and in the same
time I'll show you how to do it the way that will make your website load really really faster.
It can even save about 1 to 5 seconds.
It depends on how big your website is on loading speed.
So it's very important to do it properly.
OK.
So how to do it.
You can insert your code in back to the HMO internally or externally.
I show you now the internal way how to do it you are going to use the script doc like that and then
between the opening and closing tag you just type the script.
So for instance I would type all.
And then we'll just type test.
This is the most simple script.
It doesn't matter what is it.
What is the function or is this parentheses What is that.
All things around here that semicon other things like that we will talk about all these things later
.
Just think about it as a script that's going to alert the person on the Web site and say test or either
at all.
Hello.
And now when we were on the stakeout and we used this here we want to use the browser I'm using Firefox
and White Creek play as you can see we have got here now.
Hello.
The window saying hello.
OK.
And there's a can see then I can see the content of our website.
So that's how it works.
We had good screen that is doing something like that and that's doing it internally.
Right.
You can also post the script later.
So for example here and there are some differences because of it.
But first let's think about even thinking about putting something internally.
These are situations when we want to do something like that you want to do things like that very rarely
when you want to put something into the screen in that exact.
And only in that situation.
Why.
Because when you do something like that that code is not gonna be cached.
This is that what cached.
OK it's not going to go into the cache which is a temporary memory of your browser.
And because of it this code is gonna be loaded.
Each time the user go to another side of your website.
So it's gonna slow your website right.
So it's a good idea to have it in one place.
So for example like here.
Well we could do it like that.
So we want to decode to be here.
We don't want it to be like that and we want to import it.
So how to do that.
Well we can do something like type something like script and then we can use that attribute as our see
from that which stands for source.
And here we tag the source.
So for example like that.
And now we just imported this file here.
And when we refresh it as you can see we can see you see a hello here pretty easy right.
So it's the external way of doing this Fink in all HDMI.
We had to type here also something like pipe and say that it is that javascript script by but by default
default.
Now the screen is javascript Francine's the HD XML file.
OK.
You don't need to think about things like that anymore.
But there is as well still one small problem.
What is it.
Well look at this.
When I reload this website you can say hello and then when I click OK.
Our Web site content is loaded.
When I put this here as you can see our contard is already loaded and well I can see then hello.
Why something like that happens because.
Well I will tell you now how exactly your web page is loaded.
First thing.
You as a user would connect to your website and then you would download your HDMI Alfar.
So for example index dot h dot HMO and then something with is called a parser which is processing and
interpreting everything inside.
So for example tocks when it means something like scrape it stops totally executing well parsing other
film.
So if the script is here it will go to HDMI.
So it doesn't change the HTML document the head also.
I have the additional information of our of our website of of these Web site overtight.
OK so I have to add the title world for our user.
OK.
All of his you think that the cursor like that viewport also this is for web responsive web design and
all script.
OK so before going here I should go and execute everything inside it and then go to the body section
.
And now you might be like hey this is just one line is not gonna slow it doesn't matter.
Well in that situation.
The worst the if the website was like that.
OK.
But now imagine that your web site is really big.
Really really there is like five hundred of cards and you don't have only one script the joyous.
You have got a good like 50 or 10 what happens.
Wow.
Imagine now something like that that you would go to all these scripts.
And then after executing all the things inside it would LoDo happened.
What would happen what your user would just not see almost anything.
Right.
And after loading everything.
Then he would see the content of the website which is very bad right.
But for our users.
He would just leave probably our Web site.
We cannot allow something like that.
That's why most people just bought this scripts here.
But there is a small problem because when he puts scripts here we do not download them instantly.
Right so when the content of the website is loaded it's gonna be loaded down.
Right.
It's not so bad in most situations.
Mobot well imagine that there are ominous scripts also.
So then they are downloaded a bit later so that does not go right.
And sometimes the scripts are doing something with the layout of your website.
So they are changing something the Chloris takes other things like that they are moving something to
other place.
And now imagine that the user with the script here would just see the content of your website and this
content these are change on his eyes.
Eyes right.
He would just look at his Web site and he's going to change one of that Jasc is file is going to be
loaded.
That's also bad.
So work what to do how to how to change it.
Some people will put something skeer something here.
Yeah.
But because of HDMI five we have got something what is called a new attribute with this which is called
as sync which stands for synchronous I would type this word here as soon Crone's.
Right.
And what it means that discreate is gonna be loaded in the same time when Or other things are gonna
be loaded.
Right.
It's not gonna wait for the script to be executed which is by default how browsers are loading your
sites and it's just that you are right you are just putting this thing and everything works fine.
But be careful if you have more than one screen.
So you have something like that stupid ones get screwed to keep free.
And for example your user will download this one first.
It's gonna be a cute at first is not going to be executed then like there's been days than these then
bam bam bam bam.
Right because of it.
It's a good idea to use the word like defer which is the same as as saying Coroneos but it's gonna make
it run one by one OK.
It's up.
Wait for disk scripts to execute in that order.
So when I do it like that.
Now as you can see when I reload these Web site we can see that the content is loaded and we can see
the help right.
It's working like that.
Now if I remove this word as you can see we don't have content.
We have good content after people.
OK.
So this is the best solution you can have to do something like that and I suggest you to have all five
.
Well all scripts in an external source like that because well it's easier to maintain your code done
right.
You have got the javascript you know other files the many other files so it's easier to maintain you
know where if your script is gonna be cached so it means that your website is gonna load faster and
well.
You have to also remember that to not to create too many javascript files because if you have managed
javascript files Well it's easier to maintain your project but your web website will also load slower
because if you have a javascript Feis and HD HD to be protocol is allowing you to only download about
two files at once.
It means that there are going to be many requests to your server when the user is visiting your website
and because of it well and that because the requests are the slowest Fink's because you have you know
the user have to connect to the server where is your website and then go back.
This is something that is taking the longest time.
And when you have many javascript FAEs for example and you have to do like four times something like
that which is maybe sometimes when the server is very far one second just for you know not downloading
but just for connecting.
So its taking a lot of time and because of video.
So he's got a lot faster so the best Web site will be just one javascript file so it will be great if
you had many javascript files and then to maintain your code easier.
And then at the end when you want to put them on the web server you want to connect them but you know
connecting something like that every time when you change something what we do it takes much time.
So most time most people do not do it but you can use something what is called Ganji Yes which is the
task manager that would do it automatically for you.
I get all of the calls about this thing also.
But if you want well you can do it.
Also some manwell right.
OK so the best thing to sum up is to put the script here in the head because it will be the fastest
but you have to remember to put these key this attribute otherwise it will not be discussed.
And well you can check how is it supported because no its from 8 to 5.
You can go to it can I use dot com and type you s synchronous and here you can type your can for it
.
And as you can see when you go to for example Internet Explorer Well Internet Explorer 6 and 7 is not
supported 8 and 9 as you can see Firefox's of Firefox is not supported but when you add all these numbers
it depends where you live right.
And probably like to free people on one hand 100 coming to your Web site.
That will not support it but you need to remember that you are helping all other users to load your
website faster right.
Well they will see your web on the way.
If you put it here right but you will make enjoy your website more for users with the new one with the
new browsers.
I think that users that all browsers and those that do not enjoy it as such.
The Internet as the guys with the new browser these will make them change it faster.
Your website will load anyway.
OK thats on that lesson thank you very much.